deluxe tuning
made in germany at the heart of the
river valley
brabus transforms mercedes-benz brand
vehicles
into driving powerhouses the company's
maxim
more displacement more horsepower more
torque
[Music]
so next we'll check and see if the car
reaches its speed of 300 kilometers an
hour
900 horsepower performance tuning at
any cost of course they will then have a
car worth half a million or even
possibly one million euros
the high-end tuners of the rear valley
have been performing
supreme precision work for more than 40
years
you can't be off by even one or two
millimeters new components are developed
and manufactured in the workshop using
state-of-the-art technology
toys for the boys in the engine
department
fine tuning is carried out on a nano
scale
you need to have a different level of
know-how
the tuning premises in the city of
botrop
new base vehicles are brought here every
day step one is the quality inspection
the inspector examines the vehicles for
paintwork damage
dense and other damage that may have
occurred during transit
if a vehicle is not impeccable the
quality inspector will investigate it
immediately
for the tuning experts it's a matter of
the highest degree of precision
right from the very beginning
before its high-end upgrade like every
new arrival
this maibak is sent to the car wash dirt
is taboo in the garages because the
function of high performance tuning
parts may be compromised by impurities
after washing it's taken inside the
workshop
around 500 vehicles are converted here
every year on an area
spanning 150 000 square meters
we have different levels of
customization if you come in the morning
wanting to have a performance upgrade
fitted
this will cost 1 590 euros plus v-a-t
a couple of hours later you leave with
an additional 20 or 30 horsepower
or if you want a complete overhaul on
average this will take three months or
up to six months
afterwards you will have a vehicle
that's worth half a million or even 1
million euros and up to 900 horsepower
[Music]
briefing in the cartooners control
center team leaders and workshop
managers
meet here every morning they discuss the
production status of the orders
around 150 wish lists are pinned to the
wall
car owners from all over the world place
orders here to give their vehicles
a special personality
here we're creating a starry sky for our
customers in a g63 smart ultimate
a full leather interior with a complete
exterior remodeling
the vehicle is getting a performance
boosting kit and a valve controlled
exhaust
some customers also just want 700
horsepower speedometer
roof instruments door sill panels and a
carbon bonnet
full conversion this customer doesn't
want any chrome or silver details to be
visible or any emblems or logos
this is the kind of range we work with
the customer's favorite model is the
braabus 800 wide star
for nearly four decades the off-road
vehicle has been continually fine-tuned
in bothrop
the 2.5 ton off-roader can now be
upgraded to
900 horsepower
[Music]
the mercedes amg g63 forms the base
top speed of kilometers per hour
with a power rating of 585 horsepower
and 850 newton meters torque
after undergoing its mutation in the
rear a high-powered car
has 800 horsepower and 1000 newton
meters torque
the xl off-roader is then capable of
breaking the 100 kilometer per hour mark
in just 4.1 seconds
the transformation begins in factory one
in this configuration
the production vehicle already costs 150
000 euros
after the suv leaves the works with a
full conversion
it will be worth twice as much
a mechanic removes the standard exhaust
system
it will be replaced with a chrome plated
sport exhaust
this does not make the suv faster but
the
look and sound are intended to be as
attention grabbing as possible for the
owner
the difference is that the design and
the sound are nicer
you have a button that says sport
exhaust on it you press it
then it's in sport mode and it sounds
really great
[Music]
thirty minutes later the valve
controlled exhaust has been fitted
and the car's value has increased by 7
000 euros
time for a sound check
[Music]
this is how the car sounds in normal
mode the new component
shows what it can do at the mere touch
of a button
the mechanic is satisfied
toys for the boys throughout europe
there are noise thresholds in effect
for motor vehicles cars in this
performance class may not exceed 75
decibels
this is as loud as a washing machine in
a spin cycle
the tuners must comply with these rules
too
there are of course regulations if
someone wants a car
that is 200 decibels we simply have to
say that's not an option
this is not permitted anywhere we simply
would not do this kind of work
or if somebody wants a three kilogram
gold logo on their airbag
this has safety implications and a crash
this would fly into your face
obviously we wouldn't do it so husband
will not release this tool
in the glass hall in factory one the
fitters are replacing the original
external paneling and aerodynamic parts
they need to make way for the wide star
kit which will increase
the value of the suv by a five figure
amount
the hood consists of a carbon kit this
top piece
known as the power dome is intended to
provide the tuned engine with more
room large air ducts in the newly
installed front spoiler
supply the unit with additional oxygen
extended wings on the front and rear
axle give the vehicle an even
beefier look a standard design of
23-inch light alloy rims
and a new rear bumper give the
off-roader a sporty appearance
the stainless steel exhaust with the
throttle system provides the powerful
sound
the mechanics are assembling the new
wings a full conversion kit consists of
around 50 individual parts
these have all been painted before
assembly
the employees attach the wings to the
off-roader in a few simple steps
it's now 10 centimeters wider on either
side
enough space for chunky tires
the new 23-inch wheels are already
waiting in the warehouse next door
a colleague clamps the huge alloy wheels
machined from a single piece
into an assembly machine the sports
tires will later have to keep the two
and a half ton
car on the road at speeds of up to 240
kilometers per hour
the casing the central framework of the
tire and a special rubber compound
ensure the necessary traction
[Music]
highly tuned vehicles always operate at
their physical limits
the tire mechanic cannot afford to make
a mistake when mounting them
the consequences would be disastrous
it could get dangerous then i wouldn't
like to be sitting in the car for tire
bursts
the fact is our vehicles are indeed
faster after all
the special material and the precision
work come at a price
a set of super tires costs up to 17 000
euros
that's equivalent to a new small car
up next the balancing machine
on the road the wheels have to rotate
perfectly
the machine sensors measure the
imbalance on the axle
the location is automatically displayed
to the technician
the fitter offsets the slightest
deviation by attaching weights to the
rim
by the end of the day the tire
specialist has assembled around
50 wheels using this method
a fast car also needs powerful brakes
but the original red of the disc brake
caliper
does not appeal to everyone the color
can be changed at the customer's request
the fitters remount the resprayed brakes
a highly sensitive task error tolerance
for the high-end tuners
0.0 yeah this is the most important
component in the vehicle
no brakes means no way of stopping and
the customer could be killed
you cannot be off by one or two
millimeters it's truly precision work
the mechanic now painstakingly places
the yellow disc brake caliper onto the
brake disc
he takes his time at every step stress
could increase the error rate the
difference between custom workshop and
assembly line work
is obvious here
we're used to work the jobs were all on
tight schedules
slaving away non-stop they would use a
stopwatch to see if we could get the job
done in the set time
what matters here everything has to be
top-notch 100
everything needs to be as it should be
when tuning powerhouses such as these
it's not about time pressure but about
quality precision
and safety
back in the large glass hall the front
side of the suv
is up next the mechanics manually
assemble the new front spoiler
the employees modify four suvs here
every week
giving them the beast look
the customers want to stand out from the
crowd they're looking for a custom-made
car
something their neighbors or work
colleagues don't have
too hard here in bottom a 450 strong
staff
meet the requirements of even the most
demanding customers
globally 2 500 employees work for the
company in more than 100 countries
babus specialized in tuning
mercedes-benz cars
right from the outset more than 85
percent of the vehicles and conversions
leave germany after customization and
mainly go to asia the usa
russia and the gulf region
we work for an international clientele
chief executives
royalty formula one champions
very famous sometimes actors and
sometimes pop stars on the u.s
charts we never name names of course but
one or two of our vehicles are owned by
top celebrities
and this is of course what we do every
single day
the construction of new vehicle parts is
also among the daily tasks
strict secrecy applies here the initial
stages of development
take place in the catacombs of the plant
the design engineer prepares an ultra
modern 3d scanner
when a new vehicle model comes onto the
market the existing tuning kits
such as spoilers bumpers or wings do not
fit onto the new model
therefore new attachments have to be
designed
using the scanner the tuners generate a
digital model of the relevant vehicle
parts
the virtual 3d copy then serves as a
basis
for the new design
is a few times this large number of dots
in a row creates an optical line
and with the coupled motion we visually
get a flat surface
the light beam is emitted and recaptured
by a receiver camera
which we can see here on the other side
of the machine thanks to the
acquisitions of the emitted light beams
and the recaptured ones we then obtain
the correct
distances of the scan data
the 3d scanner measures the vehicle
contours precisely to a hundredth of a
millimeter
generating an exact digital image the
front part of the car is being scanned
here for the design of a new front
section
scanning a complete vehicle would take
up to two working days
the new 3d data of the front spoiler is
processed in the development department
the new spoiler and additional air
intakes need to fit
to the front of the vehicle
for this reason it's necessary to pay
attention
not only to the material properties but
also to safety aspects
the challenges are to be mindful of the
manufacturing considerations
for carbon fiber components we also need
to comply with two
the technical inspectors as well as
statutory regulations to ensure that our
products
are authorized on public roads
over the course of the company's 40-plus
year history
the botrop designers have developed
thousands of custom parts
the new components see the light of day
in factory 2.
the master forms of the new parts are
manufactured using
3d printers just now three newly
designed roof instrument holders
are being printed out
the model builder cleans the blanks
thoroughly with a sodium hydroxide
solution
using the sanitized prototypes the model
builders then construct a mold out of
silicon
this is used to cast all future roof
instrument holders
there are around 500 of the silicon
blocks
ready in the plastics production stores
the 10 employees in the workshop make
numerous individual parts
every day even the smallest plastic
pieces
are handcrafted
the mold for the roof instrument holders
is sealed tightly before casting
using a pneumatic stapler the worker
joins the upper and lower side of the
mold
together it's important that no liquid
plastic escapes later on
the silicon block is stored temporarily
in a curing oven
at a temperature of 70 degrees celsius
which will allow
the liquid plastic to then spread out
better in the preheated mold
the worker is now preparing the two
component compound
first of all he weighs out the
transparent hardener to the precise gram
and puts it into the vacuum casting
machine the second component is also
responsible for the color of the
eventual roof instrument holder
the composition of both elements must be
precise
[Music]
now the materials engineer takes the
silicon block from the curing oven
and fits it with three filler hoses he
then
also puts the finished mold into the
casting machine
the two components bind to form
polyurethane in the casting machine
the black resin provides excellent
dimensional accuracy when casting high
quality molded parts
to avoid the presence of abnormal
cavities caused by air pockets in the
finished workpiece
a strong under pressure is used in the
machine
the casting process takes 15 minutes
after resting for a further 45 minutes
in the curing oven
the silicon block is then opened
depending on the material the employee
may repeat this process between
20 to 80 times after which the mold
is no longer usable the freshly molded
vehicle parts
are now taken out the latest generation
instrument holders
still require further modification the
colleagues
apply the finishing touches to the new
parts
they are then painted and ready to be
installed in the car
the 150 000 square meter tuning premises
also include the engine department
here in factory 3 the high performance
engines
with up to 900 horsepower are created by
hand
in the mechanical production facility
the necessary tuning parts are
manufactured and finished
by the employees prototype parts
standard parts and development parts are
processed and produced here
so now the largest part would be a
crankcase and the smallest part of shim
in order to equip engines with more
displacement the mechanics fix the bare
crank cases into a milling machine
this 12 12-cylinder engine will be used
to power a limousine
during the milling operation the
diameter of its cylinders are enlarged
by re-boring more fuel can ultimately be
combusted
and this means more power
the bore of the engine is being enlarged
and the seating is being disassembled
because we are also fitting crankshafts
with greater stroke
a purely mechanical process turning and
milling
before the work is carried out the
engine builders determine the exact
position of the workpiece
using a 3d measuring sensor and measure
every individual cylinder precisely to a
thousandth of a millimeter
only the utmost precision guarantees a
perfect final result
meanwhile a colleague loads the machine
with the milling cutters
which cost up to 3 000 euros then
everything is ready to go
for one and a half hours the machine
works through the 12 cylinders of the
aluminum crank case
this enhances displacement from 6 to 7.3
liters
an increase of slightly more than 20
percent
the component then undergoes what is
known as the honing procedure
in this process the final hundredths of
a millimeter in the cylinder are removed
creating a perfect surface
first the specialist fits the torque
plate
this distorts the block as if it were
fully assembled
because when all the cylinder heads are
mounted the crankcase will warp
this tension is simulated by the torque
plate
this is huge this is a honing tool yet
another very special piece of equipment
here
it has diamond bars we now have to hone
out approximately four or five
hundredths
and hones cylindrically to ensure that
everything works perfectly afterwards
carefully and then go the honing tool
set with diamonds
rotates and simultaneously moves in and
out of the cylinder
this enables the final hundredths of a
millimeter to be removed
the engine expert measures repeatedly
using the extremely accurate dial
indicator
and checks if the removed layer is still
within the tolerance range
this calls for extensive experience and
a trained eye
one mistake and the 15 000 euro engine
block is ruined
after honing the inner surface of each
cylinder has the necessary cross
grinding
this is what the oil film adheres to and
allows the pistons to work with low
friction
an employee verifies the finish quality
using a microscope
the chief vehicle mechanic is looking
for silicon
the semi-metal is crucial to ensure that
the engine functions properly
here we have a cylinder made from
aluminum and silicon crystals
and now we're checking whether these
silicon crystals are sufficiently
exposed
that's the aluminum in the background
but that's just the aluminum
if both of the materials were on the
same plane the piston rings would jam
so that's why the silicon crystals which
are much harder than the aluminum are
exposed here
the fact that the piston and the piston
rings only move on the silicon crystals
means that the oil film can form nicely
among the crystals
so everything is well lubricated if the
silicon relief were too shallow
the aluminum would have to be etched
back so that the pistons don't jam in
the engine later on
[Music]
the high-end connecting rods are also
manufactured on site
they too are weighed like the motor
pistons to precisely a tenth of a gram
the employees then sort the individual
components according to weight
all 12 piston rod pairs thus have the
same mass
this is important for smooth and perfect
running of the high performance engine
[Music]
this is distinct from large-scale
production where there is greater
tolerance
the manufacturers of standard products
are not interested in this because
they see for themselves what kind of
effort is involved in weighing
everything first
and matching everything up we figure out
the smallest possible tolerance and then
further rework these parts
but this is the best way for this kind
of engine
the connecting rods connect the pistons
to the crankshaft
this too is a special component from the
tuning workshop
the crankshaft converts the in and out
motion of the pistons into torque
this rotary motion powers the car
here we have our own crankshaft which we
developed ourselves
this now has greater stroke as opposed
to stock
the connecting rod bearing stud the
middle is further apart from the main
bearing stud
compared to the production model the
piston takes a longer route as a result
ascending and descending the cylinder
further
[Music]
owing to the larger cylinder diameter
and the special crankshaft
the displacement of the 12 cylinders has
increased
by 1.3 liters more displacement
means greater performance however the
critical thing here
is not the final horsepower figure but
the increased torque
the high performance tuning is rounded
off by the company's own bi-turbo
charger
together with the increased displacement
this produces
up to an additional 300 horsepower
the turbocharger is basically powered by
the exhaust emissions
all the exhaust emissions from the
engine pass through here
they then power the exhaust gas turbine
at the rear
the axle turbine is on the same shaft
which compresses the air and forces it
into the cylinder
and correspondingly the engine receives
more air and has greater performance
as a result
a modified exhaust manifold and enlarged
turbine wheels with specially shaped
blades
raise the efficiency of the turbocharger
and thus
ensure more power
the moment of truth has finally arrived
the performance of the unit is tested on
the chassis dynamometer
various load scenarios are run through
at full throttle
to do this the technician alters the
resistance of the rollers
different scenarios are created on the
test bench
such as different gradients and slopes
we're looking to see if it actually
attains the performance we specify here
in the chassis dynamometer
in this case 800 horsepower
to ensure that the 800 horsepower
vehicles do not go through the wall
they are securely anchored to the floor
an oversized fan
and two blowers provide a powerful wind
and the supply of fresh air
so that the engine and cooling system do
not overheat during the sprint
this would result in an inaccurate
measurement reading
and possible engine damage
next we'll see if the car reaches its
speed of 300 kilometers per hour
by accelerating quickly to 300 from
stationary
[Music]
185 in 11 seconds the tester is
satisfied
[Music]
time was good so it completed the test
without incident
changes gears without any problem threw
all the gears up to 7th gear after 300
kilometers per hour it's all good
it passed the test the technician checks
up to four vehicles every day
in the development phase a prototype is
on the test bench for up to 14 days
in contrast to factory three there is a
much slower pace
in factory four the bottom-based tuners
also look after historic mercedes-benz
vehicles
there is a dedicated area for this work
the brabus classic department is both a
showroom
and a workshop here the high-class
vehicles are made to be as
good as they were in their original
condition the restoration
includes an effective anti-corrosion
protection and a two-year warranty
with unlimited kilometers the total
value of the classic cars on the
premises
around 20 million euros the hall
also houses several examples of the 300
sl
series the distinctive gull wing from
the 1950s
is one of the most iconic vehicles
around
restoration on one of these involves
several thousand working hours
it's worth the effort the rare classics
are sold
for millions of euros
this 50 year old mercedes-benz 280 sl
pagoda
is also awaiting its revival restored
pagoda cars
generally achieve market prices in
excess of 100 000 euros
virtually a bargain in the heated
vintage vehicle market
the technical manager pays a visit
before every reprocessing
he's looking for very specific pointers
because
not every vehicle is suitable for the
ambitious revitalization
process
of course at first sight this car looks
terrible but if you look closely this
car has a sound basis for restoration
because firstly it has not been involved
in an accident
and secondly and very importantly it has
matching numbers
which means the car has many of its
original components
such as the engine gearbox and for
example the bonnet
here for example the last digit of the
chassis number has been etched into the
bonnet
always important that such numbers match
up because ultimately we want to have a
car
that's not only been brilliantly
restored but also has so-called
matching numbers
the botrop team refers to the process of
reinstating old timers to their original
as new condition
as six star restoration the vehicle
is admittedly past its best but it has
the original features it had
when it came off the production line
you can see here the original welding
points
always a good indicator that this car
has definitely not been involved in an
accident
this is a very important criterion the
search for
suitable base vehicles is a global one
the luxury restoration then takes
between 12
and 18 months chassis engine gearbox
and interior every part right up to the
smallest piece of cable
is returned to its original condition in
the end
the 280 sl will have a price tag of
nearly 300 000
the euros of classic cars faithful to
the original
is a supreme discipline it demands very
particular skills from the select
employees
today young mechatronics engineers often
lack the necessary skill for this
specialized area
the apprentices can still learn a lot
from the old-school
chief vehicle mechanics
these are not pressed cars in other
words here we are working on vehicles
that are handmade
you won't find two vehicles that are
basically alike because this is work
done by hand
you need to have a different level of
know-how motor mechanics used to receive
training to learn how to bore saw and
file
this is no longer the case today the
mechanics in the classics motor group
are currently restoring
an old gearbox master and pupil
benefit from each other in unique ways
[Music]
he for example comes from south africa
and doesn't speak any german
and i teach him german and he teaches me
all the tricks he has picked up over the
years
yeah we're kind of complimenting one
another
the final inspection of a fully restored
classic car
is a meticulous process after so many
months
spent on the project every detail needs
to be perfect
under the car as well the color of the
screws on the originally restored horn
the surface of the underseal the color
of the axle parts
every cable must be laid correctly and
be made with the original material
[Music]
quite simply when a car leaves here
we're entitled to say
we have done everything truly everything
right down to the final screw to present
a perfect car
factory one back to the suv where the
focus
is on the interior the employee strips
out everything from the vehicle's
interior
one piece at a time first he removes the
side panel from the driver's door
then he dismantles all the seats
afterwards he brings the vehicle parts
to the upholstery shop
the customer wants a fully upgraded
interior
the bear car must now wait on the side
for four to five weeks
more than 20 specialists work in the
company's upholstery shop
the new seat covers and trims for
dashboards doors
and headlining are custom made by hand
and as per the customer's request
in the case of a complete installation
it's not only the visible parts that are
upgraded
but also the interiors of the glove
compartment and
the various shelves plus a completely
new floor
the upholsterers use either elk leather
ostrich leather
mastic or nubuck leather for the luxury
finish
around 3500 different shades are
available for the interior
all embellished with decorative seams
and artistically embroidered patterns
first of all the employees take apart
the seats and remove them from the
original supports
modern car seats provide even greater
comfort and therefore
have complex inner workings in addition
to the electric seat adjustment
there's air con automatic headrests and
massage functions
just to name a few
the challenge is to have all the
functions working again as soon as we
mount the seat cover back
for example the challenge with the seat
climate system that we connect
is to connect the seat heating mat back
so that all the functions are displayed
without anything missing or damaged
the interior fitter needs around 30
minutes to take apart the seat
the cover is then off and ready for the
next step
in the meantime his colleague has
already prepared the back seat
a complicated task lies ahead for her
this is the old cover and i'm using this
to make a template
because this customer wants it just as
it is stitched together here
but with an additional tuck
a tuck is a purely decorative seam small
but beautiful
the tricky part is here on the curve if
you don't follow this curved line here
in the right way
you lose the piping it's not where it
should be gone
and you have to throw the part away
the employee separates the entire back
seat cover
then she trims the leather for the new
seam a special sewing foot
and a special needle are required to do
the job
the sewer takes two working days for the
exclusive embellishment
even the floor mats are customized by
the cartooners
the finest materials a large variety of
patterns for quilting scenes
the incorporation of logos and even
led lights turn plane accessories
into exclusive custom made products
[Music]
the upholstery shop is state of the art
a computer control sewing machine
produces the elaborate decorative seams
the sewing head can rotate 360 degrees
and accurately sew more than 150
different patterns in
all kinds of leather
however the final result is only as good
as the raw material
important for the tuners in the ruer
valley is high quality leather
the surface should be natural soft and
breathable
the grain pattern has occurred naturally
and has not been engraved as is
commonplace in mass production
with standard leather we have an evenly
applied grain pattern which is fully
covered with a coating
with our leather you can see that the
leather changes greatly from the center
to the edge
reflecting the natural aspect of the
skin
you can even still see nicks and
injuries in the skin
the cow doesn't live alone in the cow
shed at some point they come up against
each other they do have horns after all
and they also have insect bites and
scars in their skin so when we use our
leather in-house and the vehicles we
obviously cannot use these sections
therefore we actually cut more from the
center of the skin which has a high
waist factor
so here we have an entire cow that is
around five square meters in size
if we were to cover an entire vehicle
interior we would need 100 square meters
that is
20 cows which we then process
[Music]
this comes at a cost a complete redesign
of the interior can cost more than 40
000 euros
in order to be able to process the
material as precisely
as possible the upholsterer sprays the
component with a two compound adhesive
after two hours of drying the adhesive
can be reactivated at any time
the process enables the employee to put
the leather in the exact position
before initiating the adhesion process
with the hot air gun
the upholsterer must ensure that no
waves or bubbles develop
once the final excess leather has been
removed the component
is upholstered
these small plastic parts from the
interior part of an suv
were once beige the handles switches
covers and face plates have been painted
olive green at the customer's request
the technician now reassembles each
individual part
not only does this require great
concentration and patience
but it also takes a lot of time
it takes a day to assemble all these
parts we have here
there are 123 individual parts from the
g-class and it will take a bit more time
until everything has been reinstalled
depending on just what is involved it
can take three or four days
this overhead control panel is
operational again
in a different color
as is the driver's seat too it goes
through the final inspection
after two and a half working days it can
now be returned to the customer in a new
color with special perforations in the
seats and backrest
red seams an embossed leather strip and
stitched logos
bit by bit the mechanic puts the
converted interior
back into the suv
the newly covered door trim is mounted
on the vehicle
the employee must ensure that all
technical functions
such as electric windows central locking
audio boxes and lights are working
perfectly
cables must not slip or get damaged
then he attaches the multifunctional
steering wheel with a new leather trim
this suv is also getting one further
extravagant visual attraction
500 optical fibers protruding from the
roofliner
with one purpose
a red starry sky is to shine over the
passengers
cost just under 20 000 euros
the fitter has taken a day and a half to
cover the roof interior with alcantara
and installed the 500 fiber optics in
precision work
over many hours now he pinches off each
one
individually to reveal luminous stars in
the car roofliner
does it say it's impostory it'll be
sitting there for a few hours working on
cutting everything to length
the team needs five weeks for a complete
interior overhaul
such bespoke orders are routine for the
tuning pros
very little can still surprise them
one customer wanted ostrich leather
ostrich is rather limited in terms of
its shape and size you need a few of
these skins to do an interior
but there was more to the special
request it didn't only have to be
red ostrich leather but also red carpet
inside and the car
matte black on the outside very unusual
indeed but we get this sort of thing
daily this is how we make our living
after six months the total overhaul of
the suv is done
its transformation to the brabus 800 is
complete
finally the highly tuned vehicles are
driven to the inspection
the quality inspector will spot every
error
the newly fitted brake calipers receive
particular attention
this is of vital importance not only for
the customer
but also for the inspector because he's
about to put the pedal to the metal
for the first test drive
[Music]
just checking here to see if the cabling
and in particular this brake caliper
that we have painted are tight
and then we're not losing any hydraulic
fluid here
because otherwise we'd have a problem
not having any breaks in the test drive
not something you want of course for a
vehicle of this kind with so much power
in the case of large scale conversions
the quality inspector
will manage no more than one final
inspection in a day
the check is too extensive and detailed
his trained eye is now focused on the
hull
the paint has to be unblemished and the
clearance is uniform
he pays particular attention to the
forged rims
in the case of a five-figure sum for a
set of new tires
there is zero tolerance
i'm kind of like the eye of the customer
i'm looking as the customer would be
looking yeah
next he gets to work on the interior
every individual function in the vehicle
is tested by him
door locks seat belts headrests storage
compartments
the expert feels his way looking
touching and listening
constantly on the lookout for any minor
defects or faults
all his senses are needed for the
quality control
[Music]
yeah in fact you can hear or sense if
the motors are working
the quality inspector will need to look
and touch the vehicle hundreds of times
before he starts the test drive after
the final function tests
it drives the high-end vehicle onto the
test track
this is located on the adjacent tuning
[Music]
premises
the helipad serves as the location for
an initial endurance test
where the super-rich normally land is
where the severe test begins
for the tuned vehicle
we are now at the roundabout and here we
are checking to see if the chassis
drifts or
bends somewhere
from the roundabout it's taken directly
over to the cobblestone track
the car is well and truly shaken and
bumped around
now the suspension has to demonstrate
what it's capable of
and the inspector listens to see if all
the vehicle parts are tight and secure
then the 800 horsepower vehicle speeds
over the sinus wave track
the heavyweight must not drift here
either
slam on the brakes a big turn and return
to the home straight
when kick down is activated and then
back
the suv flexes its muscles on the test
track
as you've noticed the vehicle is
tremendously powerful
if as i said before you really put your
foot down it can start to spin
you have to be careful when driving such
a vehicle
this car has been inspected and approved
and is now ready for delivery
but before loading it will be washed by
hand
the cleaning technician has an array of
car care products on hand
to make the luxury model gleam after its
test drive
here we have a calcium remover
windscreen cleaner
liquid polish rim cleaner insect remover
and car shampoo the buttrop team washes
the vehicle by hand
the experienced employee proceeds with
great care
they can't afford any scratches to the
paintwork this close to delivery
i wash around 10 to 15 cars a day it
just depends on how busy it is
now one millimeter at a time he cleans
the exterior and the interior
using a sponge high pressure washer and
polishing cloth
he needs one hour for the extensive
cleaning
then the brabus 800 can leave the
workshop
[Music]
the luxury car is however not driven to
its owner
to make sure that it reaches its final
destination undamaged
it's loaded onto a transporter belonging
to the company
the truck has space for two vehicles
once the suv is secured the journey can
begin by land
to the nearest port or to an airport and
from there
to anywhere in the world